bps-europe.net 2014-09-19

# BPS Europe

Business plans are sensitive issues that must be well protected. All BPS consultants adhere to a strict code of conduct and have signed a confidentiality statement.  

**BPS and DATA PROTECTION**

BPS is committed to the following policies which protect your privacy and comply with current international Data Protection laws and regulations in respect of personal data. We will only obtain personal data from you for specified and lawful purposes and any personal data obtained will be processed fairly and lawfully with regard to these principles: 

| a.| 

Disclosure to third parties - we do not disclose personal information to third parties, except where you have given your consent or where we have a legal obligation to do so.   
  
---|---  
b.| 

Use of personal data – we collect personal data for use in the normal course of our business. We may use your contact details that you provide to us to inform you of relevant opportunities, developments and events, unless you decide to opt out. We do not provide your details to third parties for any marketing or promotional purposes, except where you have given your explicit consent. We will only process the individual data which you provide to us for the intended purpose. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that the data held is adequate, relevant and not excessive for such purposes.  
  
c.| 

Information sharing – we may need to share personal information with other companies within the BPS Group. This may include companies, offices or data centres outside the European Economic Area. All these Group companies follow the same Data Protection policy and maintain the same levels of confidentiality and security.  
  
d.| 

Security – we take all reasonable steps to protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information.  
  
e.| 

Accuracy – we take all reasonable steps to keep your personal information accurate and, where necessary, up to date.  
  
f.| 

Retention of data – we take all reasonable steps to retain data only for the duration of the purpose for which it was obtained. When requested, we will delete personal information from current operational systems where it is no longer required. We may need to continue holding some details about you after the relationship with us has ended, for example for legal and regulatory purposes.  
  
g.| 

Policy changes – if it is necessary to disclose any of your personal information in a way that is inconsistent with this policy, we will post notice of the proposed change on this page so that you have the opportunity to opt out of such disclosure.   
  
Your rights – we take all reasonable steps to uphold your rights to protect your personal data, including the right to update, amend or obtain information on any personal data on you which we hold.

In the pursuit of the BPS Project, the Contractor and the Members, hereafter referred to as the signatories, have agreed the following provisions in addition to the rules laid down in the membership agreement and its constitutive parts: 

**Article 1**

The signatories will keep confidential any data, documents or other information communicated to them on a confidential basis or the disclosure of which may be prejudicial to one of them. This obligation shall no longer apply, where the content of these data, documents or other information becomes publicly available through work or actions lawfully performed outside this contract and not based on activities under it, where these data, documents or other information have been communicated without any confidentiality restrictions or where the disclosing party subsequently waives their confidentiality.   

**Article 2**

When performing consulting work, the signatories will use any information acquired only in this particular context and not make it available to third parties in a way that those might be able to identify the source. This restriction does not apply to information publicly known, being subject to a waiver from the entity to be consulted, provably been elaborated independently or lawfully gained by third parties on other grounds.  

**Article 3**

When entering or considering to enter into a business relationship with a third party in relation to the BPS Project, the signatories respect their role as service providers to the project and act accordingly. Each signatory engages to brief SystemConsult Theis & Partner GmbH in D – 72555 Metzingen in the event of any potential or manifest conflict of interest.  

**Article 4**

Where appropriate, the signatories inform SystemConsult Theis & Partner GmbH in D – 72555 Metzingen well in advance of all changes in the persons working on the project or about alterations in their affiliation to other companies.  

**Article 5**

The signatories respond to queries within two working days.  

**Article 6**

All personnel put on this Project must respect this Code of Conduct and the signatories provide evidence to SystemConsult Theis & Partner GmbH in D – 72555 Metzingen that they have taken the necessary measures in this context.

**Confidentiality Statement**

As a BPS consultant, I may gain information via my consultation activity considered to be confidential by those consulted and by the Project Team, which is therefore not to be disclosed towards any third person.

I will only use information acquired when consulting on individual business plans in this particular context, treat it confidentially, and not make it available to third persons in a way that those might be able to identify the source. 

This confidentiality statement does not concern information which is publicly known, which has provably been elaborated independently, or which has been lawfully gained by third persons on other grounds. 

Name:  
Institution:  
Address:  
Phone:  
Fax:  
Place, Date:  
Signature:
